export const INFORMATIONCOMMUNICATIONTECHA2016 = [

{
id: "question1",
question: "The coding schemes used to represent data are",
A: "EBCDCI and ASCII.",
B: "EDCBIC and ASCII.",
C: "EBCDIC and ASCII.",
D: "EDCBCI and ASCII.",
answer: "C. EBCDIC and ASCII",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question: "To enable a database user hold all changes made to a master file, use the",
A: "batch file.",
B: "dynamic master file.",
C: "progam file.",
D: "transaction file.",
answer: "D. Transaction file",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question: "The technology used in the control of machine tools by computer is called",
A: "computer assisted learning.",
B: "computer assisted manufacturing.",
C: "computer aided design.",
D: "computer based testing.",
answer: "B. Computer-assisted manufacturing",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question: "To improve the appearance of a layout, add more",
A: "clipart.",
B: "font.",
C: "frames.",
D: "white spaces.",
answer: "D. White spaces",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question: "To open the Go To dialogue box in a spreadsheet, press the keyboard key",
A: "Fl.",
B: "F2",
C: "F3",
D: "F12",
answer: "A. F1",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question: "The computer stores the memory, date, time, etc settings in the",
A: "BIOS chip.",
B: "CMOS chip.",
C: "SIM Chip.",
D: "Processor chip.",
answer: "B. CMOS chip",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question: "Systems software include the following except",
A: "Loaders.",
B: "Inventory Control.",
C: "Language Translators.",
D: "Operating Systems.",
answer: "B. Inventory Control",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question: "The programming language specifically developed for scientific application is",
A: "BASIC.",
B: "COBOL.",
C: "FORTRAN.",
D: "VISUAL BASIC.",
answer: "C. FORTRAN",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question: "A substitute for a repeated use of IF statement is a",
A: "DO...LOOP block.",
B: "FOR...NEXT block.",
C: "SELECT CASE block.",
D: "WHILE...WEND block.",
answer: "C. SELECT CASE block",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question: "Connecting computers to cable segments that branch out from a single point or hub is referred to as",
A: "bus topology.",
B: "mesh topology.",
C: "ring topology.",
D: "star",
answer: "D. Star",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question: "Which of the following database keys uniquely identifies a record?",
A: "Duplicate key",
B: "Foreign key",
C: "Indexing key",
D: "Primary key",
answer: "D. Primary key",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question: "The word bit refers to",
A: "the value zero or one.",
B: "the value zero or more.",
C: "central processing unit.",
D: "central processing unit instructions.",
answer: "A. The value zero or one",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question: "A centre designed for storing, processing and retrieving information for dissemination on demand by users is called",
A: "complaints centre.",
B: "help desk.",
C: "information centre.",
D: "request centre.",
answer: "C. Information centre",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question: "The following are elements of multimedia except",
A: "audio.",
B: "graphics.",
C: "icon",
D: "video.",
answer: "C. Icon",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question: "With the same font type, which of the following is typically the longest?",
A: "Dot",
B: "Em Dash",
C: "En Dash",
D: "Hyphen",
answer: "B. Em Dash",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question: "Which of the following operators is used for concatenation in spreadsheet application?",
A: "Ampersand",
B: "Apostrophe",
C: "Exclamation",
D: "Hash",
answer: "A. Ampersand",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question: "Which of the following printers produces the highest quality print-outs?",
A: "Dot Matrix",
B: "Ink Jet",
C: "Laser",
D: "Line",
answer: "C. Laser",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question: "Which of the following devices represents a pen-controlled handheld computer that performs two-way messaging?",
A: "Microcontroller",
B: "Smart Box",
C: "Information Appliance",
D: "Personal Digital Assistant",
answer: "D. Personal Digital Assistant",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question: "Common features of application software include",
A: "control bus.",
B: "storage devices.",
C: "icons and dialogue boxes.",
D: "passwords for authentication.",
answer: "C. Icons and dialogue boxes",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question: "Backing up files is a routine process that enable files to be",
A: "saved on a disk.",
B: "hidden from hackers and spammers.",
C: "used in case of damage to the main files.",
D: "used in peripherals that are connected to the computer.",
answer: "C. Used in case of damage to the main files",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question: "Which of the following features is not true about fourth generation languages (4GLs)?",
A: "It reduces errors in programming.",
B: "It enhances programmers efficiency.",
C: "It increases skill levels required of users.",
D: "It minimizes users efforts to obtain information from the computer.",
answer: "C. It increases skill levels required of users",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question: "Which of the statements below is true about the use of a title element in a web page?",
A: "It is only used when the page is printed.",
B: "It displays a text in the title bar of the web browser.",
C: "It does not make the title bar visible to the user.",
D: "It displays a message in a pop-up box when a user visits the page.",
answer: "B. It displays a text in the title bar of the web browser",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question: "Handshaking is a term used to describe the",
A: "interrogation of shared terminals.",
B: "break in contact at the end of a session.",
C: "sign-on procedure for bulletin board service.",
D: "initial contact between communicating computers.",
answer: "D. Initial contact between communicating computers",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question24",
question: "An address that points to a specific resource of the web is called",
A: "gopher.",
B: "home page.",
C: "uniform resource locator.",
D: "electronic data interchange.",
answer: "C. Uniform Resource Locator",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question: "The following are database objects except",
A: "queries.",
B: "relationships.",
C: "reports.",
D: "tables.",
answer: "B. Relationships",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question: "To enter a field to display instead of the actual characters in a database, use the command",
A: "IME Mode.",
B: "Index.",
C: "Index Mask.",
D: "Validation Rule.",
answer: "C. Input Mask",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question: "Which of the following is an interactive computer program that helps users to solve problems?",
A: "Robot",
B: "Expert System",
C: "Perception System",
D: "Natural Language",
answer: "B. Expert System",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question: "The hexadecimal number 64 in decimal equivalent is",
A: "24",
B: "100.",
C: "110.",
D: "212.",
answer: "B. 100",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question: "A recorded event having to do with routine process is called",
A: "data.",
B: "information.",
C: "item.",
D: "transaction.",
answer: "D. Transaction",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question: "Which of the following is not a facility available to users of desktop publishing?",
A: "Design Checker",
B: "Frames",
C: "Name Box",
D: "Publication Gallery",
answer: "C. Name Box",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question: "To move to a specific cell in a worksheet, enter data in the",
A: "formula box.",
B: "name box.",
C: "search box.",
D: "zoom box.",
answer: "B. Name box",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question: "When a user creates two or more separate windows containing part of the spreadsheet that can be viewed, such a user has created",
A: "panes.",
B: "sections.",
C: "subsets.",
D: "views.",
answer: "A. Panes",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question: "Which disk operating system configuration should a user check, if a device is not loading properly?",
A: "AUTOEXEM.BAT",
B: "BOOT.INI",
C: "CONFIG.SYS",
D: "SYSTEM.INI",
answer: "C. CONFIG.SYS",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question: "Data to be processed by the microprocessor is temporarily stored in",
A: "the auxiliary storage.",
B: "backing storage.",
C: "main storage.",
D: "random access memory.",
answer: "D. Random Access Memory",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question: "Which of the following monitors uses a vacuum tube?",
A: "Cathode Ray Tube",
B: "Flat Panel Display",
C: "Gas Plasma Display",
D: "Liquid Crystal Display",
answer: "A. Cathode Ray Tube",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question: "How many devices including the controller can SCSI-I support?",
A: "8",
B: "16",
C: "24",
D: "32",
answer: "A. 8",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question: "The following information are stored on a computer's CMOS chip except",
A: "date and time.",
B: "memory information.",
C: "printer configuration.",
D: "hard drive configuration.",
answer: "C. Printer configuration",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question: "Which of the following is not a font style?",
A: "Bold",
B: "Italic",
C: "Regular",
D: "Superscript",
answer: "D. Superscript",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question: "Every operating system must be able to perform the following functions except",
A: "control resources.",
B: "distribute resources.",
C: "reclaim resources.",
D: "put resources into use.",
answer: "C. Reclaim resources",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question: "The output of running the following program code is: RST=17 IF (RST>=17) THEN PRINT RST IF (RST>17) THEN PRINT RST IF (RST<>17)  THEN PRINT RST",
A: "17",
B: "17,17",
C: "RST",
D: "17.00",
answer: "A. 17",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question41",
question: "The HTML tag <body bgcolor=...> will create a",
A: "hived body.",
B: "framed body.",
C: "dotted lines in a browser.",
D: "coloured background in a browser.",
answer: "D. Coloured background in a browser",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question: "The HTML tag <!-- --> is used to indicate",
A: "comments.",
B: "paragraphs.",
C: "programming codes.",
D: "sections.",
answer: "A. Comments",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question: "Which of the following is not a loop control structure?",
A: "DO",
B: "FOR",
C: "IF",
D: "WHILE",
answer: "C. IF",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question: "The practice of enveloping one protocol inside the header of another is called",
A: "emulation.",
B: "encapsulation.",
C: "sealing.",
D: "translation.",
answer: "B. Encapsulation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question: "Which of the following is the same as http://127.0.0.1 in the address bar of a web client?",
A: "http://local",
B: "http://hostip",
C: "http://localhost",
D: "http://www.local.com",
answer: "C. http://localhost",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question: "The maximum data rate that can be transmitted over UTP Cat 3 cable is",
A: "10 Mbps.",
B: "16 Mbps.",
C: "32 Mbps.",
D: "100 Mbps.",
answer: "A. 10 Mbps",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question: "The object that stores commands to retrieve data from a created database is called a",
A: "Form.",
B: "Query.",
C: "Report.",
D: "Table.",
answer: "B. Query",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question: "The appropriate data type that can be used to store customers' telephone numbers in a database is",
A: "DATE.",
B: "MEMO.",
C: "NUMBER.",
D: "TEXT.",
answer: "D. TEXT",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question49",
question: "What will the following SQL syntax do? \nSELECT Fieldiist \nFROM tablename \nIN anotherdatabase.mdb  \nWHERE condition \nGROUP BY fieldiist \nHAVING conditions for fields that are grouped ORDER By fieldiist",
A: "Add records to a table.",
B: "Update records in a table.",
C: "Make a table from resulting values.",
D: "Select data from tables and display result in rows and columns.",
answer: "D. Select data from tables and display result in rows and columns",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question50",
question: "Which of the following displays information in multimedia form?",
A: "Archie",
B: "Usenet",
C: "File Transfer Protocol",
D: "World Wide Web",
answer: "D. World Wide Web",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]